

Michael Rukundo Knabe

Full Stack Web and App Developer

Certified Full Stack Web and App developer with a business mindset and a huge interest in innovation and new technologies. Proficient in Frontend and Backend.

Driven team-player with great communication skills and with previous experience within the tech industry through managing frontend, backend and design experts as well as third party technical service providers. Experienced in project-, product- and business development.

Contact Info

+49 173 3034474

mrknabe2@gmail.com

Personal Info

10245 Berlin, Germany 29.07.1990

Key Skills

Product Management
Project Management

Problem Solving

Responsive Design

JavaScript

React.js

HTML5

CSS3

Node.js

Express

APIs

Software Testing

Tools

VS Code

Git and GitHub

Console

Jira

Salesforce / Hubspot

Languages

German: Native
English: Excellent
Spanish: Fluent

Interests

Sports: Running and Fitness Music: Acoustic Guitar

Education

06/2020 - 10/2020

Berlin

09/2016 - 10/2017

Lisbon / Copenhagen

09/2015 - 10/2017 Copenhagen

10/2011 - 02/2015 Cologne

09/2007 - 06/2010 Frechen

i iedileii

09/2006 - 06/2007 Shaftesbury WBS CODING SCHOOL

Certificate in Full Stack Web and App Development

Master of Science in international Management

CEMS - The Global Alliance in Management Education

Final Grade: A-

Master of Science in International Business

Copenhagen Business School

Final Grade: 1.7

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

University of Cologne

Final Grade: 2.2

A-Levels (Abitur)

Final Grade: 1.7

Year Abroad

Work Experience

12/2019 - 06/2020 Berlin

Senior Business Development Manager

GoLiving

 Cooperation with large real estate companies short-term for leasing, mid-term for joint project development in Berlin, Cologne and Düsseldorf

 Identification of customer needs and development of suitable use cases

 Creation and continuous development of a corporate pitch deck and business development playbook

05/2019 - 10/2019 Berlin Project Manager Mobility Apps - MaaS

Mobimeo GmbH (Deutsche Bahn AG)

 Strategic partner management: analysis of needs, definition of product scope & integration roadmap

 Consult partners on market entry strategy and comms strategy, train staff on products for customer service

Management of external tech service providers

 Highlight project risks and develop mitigation options, ensure timely delivery and compliance with SLAs

 Manage various teams composed of product, engineering, design and market experts 11/2017 - 04/2019 Berlin

B2B Partnerships Manager - SaaS

Telefónica Germany NEXT GmbH (Minodes)

- Product Owner White Label: product development, market analysis, development and execution of channel strategy as well as first partners ahead of schedule
- Scaled up White Label to be major revenue channel
- Strategic development of partnerships throughout the entire process from acquisition and relationship building to closing, execution of roll-outs and cross-& upselling
- Planned and executed negotiations, onboardings and workshops with C-level executives
- Cross functional project management to ensure compliance with SLAs and make partners happy
- Promotion from SDR to Partnerships Manager

Internships & Volunteer Work

02/2016 - 05/2016 Copenhagen

Consultant

180 Degrees Consulting, Client: Non-Profit-Organization

- Analysed the client's organizational structure, employee incentives and fundraising strategy
- Developed and implemented new vision & mission statements, and a new organizational structure
- Created action plan to reach fundraising goals

12/2014 - 05/2015 Berlin

Business Developer

Rocket Internet SE (EatFirst)

- Set up, improved and executed operations processes
- Negotiations with business partners & suppliers
- Identification, analysis & reporting on operations KPIs

09/2013 - 12/2013 Cologne / Dortmund

Consultant

OSCAR GmbH, Client: Big Public Contractor

- Analysed the client's cost accounting processes and developed a new system for enhanced performance
- Carried out test runs of the concept
- Summary: The client's directors commissioned a follow-up project for companywide implementation

11/2011 - 09/2012 Cologne

Project Lead

AIESEC-Cologne (Student Society)

- Led a team of eight students
- Organized accommodation and internships in local NGOs for 20 volunteers from 13 nations

10/2010 - 06/2011 Madrid

Volunteer

Internationaler Bund e.V. – full-time

- Took a three months intensive Spanish course
- Worked six months as a volunteer in a kindergarten